Read family papers LCP.Read
Library Company of Philadelphia
The subseries “Writings and Research by General John Meredith Read II” consists of numerous notes, drafts, and correspondence related to General Meredith Read’s various published and unpublished writings. The subseries is divided into two groupings, each arranged chronologically. The first grouping dates from 1865 to 1896 and contains mostly items directly related to or produced by General Meredith Read’s writing. The second grouping is an autograph collection of correspondence that dates from 1710 to 1779. Of particular interest are the materials related to his draft of “Life and Lineage of His Royal Highness Prince Albert” and his self-published book A Historical Inquiry Concerning Henry Hudson. The related research notes, drafts, advertisements, pamphlets, shipment forms and correspondence written by General Read to various associates provide illustrative examples of the process of self-publication in the mid- to late- 19th century. Also of note are the research materials gathered by General Meredith Read to aid in his writing of the posthumously published book “Historic Studies in Vaud, Berne, and Savoy from Roman Times to Voltaire, Rousseau and Gibbon.” The various notes and correspondence comment on the social history of France in the seventeenth and the eighteenth centuries. Also related to his “Historic Studies” are the numerous pieces of correspondence he collected for their autograph value, including several items written and signed by Voltaire, Edward Gibbon, King Frederick II of Prussia, and other 18th century correspondence, mostly written in French.
The series “Harmon Pumpelly Read” consists primarily of scrapbook materials, correspondence and ephemera that relates mostly to General Meredith Read’s son Harmon Pumpelly Read. The series dates from 1880 to circa 1908 and is arranged chronologically. Included in the series is a scrapbook of the death of Harmon’s father, General Meredith Read, as well as various pieces of ephemera such as playbills and blank postcards. There are a few items of business correspondence and financial materials such as bills, receipts, and accounting ledgers. Of particular interest in the correspondence is Harmon Pumpelly Read’s communication with his mother-in-law, Madame de Carron, who was confined to a mental hospital in Hartford against her will, presumably committed by Harmon himself. Madame de Carron wrote several angry letters to Harmon Pumpelly Read to express her outrage about his actions against her and even accused him of corrupting her relationship with her daughter. There also are some letters written in French by Madame de Carron to one or more of her daughters describing her anguish at being committed to the mental hospital as well as a few letters written by Harmon complaining about his mother-in-law’s irrational behavior. The correspondence provides researchers with insight into late 18th century mental health, women’s health, and family life.
The series “John Meredith Read III: Autobiography and family history” contains one bound volume dating circa 1900. The volume contains a hand-written memoir of the life of John Meredith Read III, who was Harmon Pumpelly Read’s brother and General Meredith Read’s other son. The memoir provides supplementary insight into other genealogical research found elsewhere in the collection.
The series “James Read account book for Rings End and Point (part 9)” consists of a single bound financial volume, dating from 1761 to 1765. The account book contains financial records for James Read, who was the brother of George Read, the signer of the Declaration of Independence.
The series “Collected Meredith family papers” is a collection separately acquired and added to the Read Family collection. The series contains mostly correspondence written by Read family members to each other, dating from 1667 to 1892. The series is arranged in chronological order. Items of correspondence are from Samuel Meredith to his wife Peggy Meredith, Martha Read to Peggy Meredith, James Gibson to Peggy Meredith, John Read to Thomas Meredith, Thomas Meredith Maxwell to General Meredith Read and several others. Also included is a copy of a letter written by Thomas Jefferson to Samuel Meredith.
Conditions Governing Access note
This collection is open for research use, on deposit at the Historical Society of Pennsylvania, 1300 Locust Street, Philadelphia, PA 19107. For access, please contact the Historical Society at 215-732-6200 or visit http://www.hsp.org.
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
Bequest of Marguerite de Carron Read, 1940.
Related Archival Materials note
Dickinson College: John Meredith Read papers, 1818-1870.
Library of Congress: Read family papers, circa 1568-1906.
New York Public Library: Clymer-Meredith-Read family papers, 1675-1902 (bulk 1760s-1850s).
Rosenbach Museum and Library: George Read papers, 1766.
University of Delaware: Read family papers, 1756-1833, MSS #237; Samuel Meredith papers, 1730-1823 (bulk 1764-1823), MSS #240; and Samuel Meredith letters and documents, 1786-1798, MSS #239.
University of Rochester: John Meredith Read papers, circa 1870-1907.
Collis, Charles H.T., (Charles Henry Tucky), 1838-1902; Collis, Septima M., (Septima Maria), 1842-1917; Cornell University.; Freemasons. Grand Lodge of Pennsylvania.; Meredith; Read, Harmon Pumpelly, b. 1860; Read, John Meredith, 1797-1874; Read, John Meredith, 1837-1896; Read, John, 1769-1854; Read; United Church of Christ.; Business records; Clippings; Correspondence; Deeds; Diaries; Ephemera; Estate records; Family papers; Financial records; France; Genealogical tables; Greece; Law; Legal documents; Manuscripts; New York (State); Philadelphia (Pa.); Photographs; Poems; Politics & international relations; Property records; Scrapbooks; Textbooks; United States--History--Civil War, 1861-1865
- Series I. Family history and genealogy
  - Cadwalader and Howell families, genealogical correspondence, 1883-1886 (Volume 1)
  - Genealogical research scrapbook on Thomas Read by General John Meredith Read, 1885 (Volume 2)
  - Genealogical and historical scrapbook about Captain Thomas Read, 1883-1885 (Volume 3)
  - Portraits and illustrations relating to genealogical research, circa 1876 (Volume 4)
  - The Ross family genealogical research conducted by General John Meredith Read, 1872-1874 (Volume 5)
  - Correspondence to General John Meredith Read about family history, 1882-1886 (Volume 6)
  - Correspondence from Major Harmon Read to General John Meredith Read regarding Ross and Read families, 1882 August (Volume 7)
  - Delaware Society of the Cincinnati scrapbook, 1895-1909 (Volume 8)
  - Autograph collection: William Penn to Gookin, 1710 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Autograph collection: Bill of ship Catherine, 1772 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Autograph collection: Mrs. Horatio Gates to Mr. Meredith, 1778 February 4 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Autograph collection: George Washington to Samuel Meredith, 1780 September 9, 1790 March 9 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Autograph collection: Governor Robert Morris to Samuel Meredith, 1789 July 25, 1789 September 13, 1790 May 28 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Autograph collection: George Washington Commission to Samuel Meredith, 1789 August 4 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Autograph collection: Timothy Pickering to John Read Jr., 1797 November 17 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Autograph collection: Commission to John Read I from John Forsyth, 1798 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Autograph collection: Mrs. Meredith to General Meredith about General Washington, undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Genealogical notes: George Ross of Pitcalnie manuscript notes, undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Genealogical notes: Descent of the Read family from the Ancient Earls of Ross, undated (Box 1, Folder 11-12)
  - Genealogical notes: Read and Pumpelly family genealogical notes and research, undated (Box 1, Folder 13-14)
- Series II. Deeds (Box 2)
  - Thomas Overton to Northstede Manor, 1403 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Regarding Andrewe Reade and land in Berks County, 1577 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - William Ifenwick to Phillipp Gibbon, 1609 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Suffolk One-Honse Manor to Family of Reade, 1624 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Unidentified (in French), 1650 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Comelius Vermigden to Mary Reade, 1684 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Catherine Dowager to Thomas Meredith, 1732 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Christian Hartell to Petrus Emundus Elmendorph, 1752 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - St. Ann's Church in Blackfryers, 1757 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Helena Van Keuren to William Elingedorf, 1768 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Paul Zantzinger to Sebastian Graff, 1773 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Jacob Cooper to Henry Casdorp, 1776 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - William Ball to Henry Hill, 1776 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Charles Ruston to Charles Young, 1776 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Joanna Young to John Waldrick, 1782 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Joanna Young to Charles Tice, 1783 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Joanna Young to John Sproson, 1784 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Joanna Young to John Sproson, 1784 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - John Sproson to David Dreaclery Benonery, 1784 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - John Sproson to John Edling, 1784 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - John Sproson to John Edling, 1785 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - John Edling to Joanna Young, 1788 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - James Ash to John Cummings, 1788 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Joshua Fisher to Sarah Fisher, 1789 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Catharine Cropper to Thomas Ruston, 1793 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Nathaniel Browning to Thomas Bryan, 1794 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Thomas Morris to Charles Wilkes, 1802 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence Regarding Elizabeth Bleecker Religious Conviction, 1811 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Cadwalader Evans, Jr. to William Lee, 1813 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Jacob Fitler to Adolph Ehringhaus, 1813 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Robert F. Smith to John Cochran, 1814 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Adolph Ehringhaus and wife to Charles W. Hulz, 1814 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Jacob Cist, Luzerne County Treasurer to Henry Clymer, circa 1816 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - George M. Hollenback to Thomas Meredith, 1820 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Jacob S. Cunitz to Thomas G. Leaffer, 1829 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Sharp D. Lewis to Thomas Meredith, 1830 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Samuel Davis to James Clark, 1848 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Unidentified (in French), undated (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Series III. Bills and receipts, 1787-1798
  - 1787-1798 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - 1792-1794 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - 1796-1802 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - 1800-1805 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - 1821-1824 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - 1825-1828 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - 1829, 1831, 1832, 1834 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - 1835-1838 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - 1839-1842 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - 1843-1847 (Box 6, Folder 3)
- Series IV. John Read I
  - Bills and Receipts: John Read Jr. receipt numbers 233-284, 1796 January 6-1796 December 6 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Bills and Receipts: List of fees, 1797-1807 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Bills and Receipts: Professional receipt book, 1800-1818 (Volume 78)
  - Bills and Receipts: John Read Jr. expense book, 1806-1809 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Bills and Receipts: John Read Jr. expense book, 1812-1814 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Bills and Receipts: Family expense book, 1813-1814 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Bills and Receipts, 1814 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Bills and Receipts, 1814-1815 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Bills and Receipts: Harrisburg Bank with John M. Read, 1816-1821 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Bills and Receipts: Receipt book, 1817 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Bills and Receipts: Invoices, 1818-1834 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Bills and Receipts: John Read Jr. expense book, 1819-1820 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Bills and Receipts: John Read Jr., 1822-1827 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Bills and Receipts: Invoices for work done, materials used, 1827-1854 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Bills and Receipts: Isaac Kite expense book, 1828 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Bills and Receipts, 1829-1830 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Bills and Receipts, 1832-1833 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Bills and Receipts, 1833, 1834, 1848, 1850 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Bills and Receipts: An account of John read's family and other expenses, 1835-1848 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Bills and Receipts, 1849 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Bills and Receipts: The Trenton Banking Company with John Read, 1851-1854 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Bills and Receipts: Accounts of monies from income and stocks purchased, 1852-1854 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Bills and Receipts: Index to professional receipts, undated (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Business Papers: Correspondence, legal notes, memorandum, account information, freight information, 1761-1779 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Business Papers: Correspondence, summons, land tract information, estate papers, 1780-1789 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Business Papers: Correspondence and business papers (mostly involving Benjamin Gibbs), 1790-1798 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Business Papers: Tuscarora lands, Bradford County, PA, deeds, 1793, 1813 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Business Papers: Promissory notes, 1795 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Business Papers: Correspondence, shopping lists, receipts, 1795-1809 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Business Papers: Tax book exhibiting what taxes have been paid on each particular land tract for the year 1796 (Volume 79)
  - Business Papers: Correspondence and legal notes, 1796-1824 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Business Papers: Articles of agreement, indentures, 1798, 1809, 1818 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Business Papers: Estate of Thaddeus Goodyear; Tuscarora land, Bradford County, PA information, 1798-1834 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Business Papers: Correspondence, indentures, receipts, 1798-1814 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Business Papers: Land tract information, legal papers, correspondence, 1798-1799 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Business Papers: Accounts and correspondence, 1800 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Business Papers: Legal documents and correspondence regarding Nicholas Le Favre, 1800-1815 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Business Papers: Court case notes, indentures, promissory notes, 1800-1849 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Business Papers: Legal documents concerning the ship Cordelia, [packet] Pennsylvania, ship Three Sisters, and others, 1801-1821 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Business Papers: Correspondence, legal notes, memorandum, account information, freight information, 1801 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Business Papers: Correspondence, indentures, promissory notes, receipts, Estate of Robert Wiley, 1802 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Business Papers: Promissory notes, house-building contracts, debt, lawsuits, 1802-1807 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Business Papers: Papers and correspondence with Robert Clark regarding home on Baskin Island, Dauphin County, Pennsylvania, 1802-1803 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Business Papers: Promissory notes and legal correspondence, 1802-1827 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Business Papers: John Read's Philadelphia Bank account book, 1803 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Business Papers: Correspondence, deeds, indentures, promissory notes, warrant, 1803 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Business Papers: Financial and legal notes, 1803-1812 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Business Papers: Correspondence, deeds for Luzerne County, Pennsylvania, indentures, 1804 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Business Papers: Saint Michael's Church financial lists; family correspondence, promissory notes, 1804-1830 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Business Papers: Newspaper clippings, papers relating to David Rittenhouse Water, correspondence with Joseph Webb, 1804-1835 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Business Papers: Correspondence, financial papers, covenant, land tracts, receipts, 1805 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Business Papers: Correspondence and notes regarding Nicholas Le Favre, 1805-1815 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Business Papers: Correspondence, deeds, indentures, 1806 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Business Papers: Correspondences, court cases, financial papers, insurance policy, 1807 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Business Papers: Promissory notes, court summons, trade contracts, 1807 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Business Papers: Correspondence, deeds, indentures, elections, receipts, 1807-1839 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Business Papers: Correspondence, Luzerne County, Pennsylvania land tract information, court cases, papers regarding Wayne County, 1808 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Business Papers: Correspondence, deed information, land tract information, notes, 1809 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Business Papers: Notes to self by John Read Jr., 1808-1810 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Business Papers: Indentures and promissory notes, 1809-1813 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Business Papers: Asylum Company legal documents, court case notes, court summons, 1809-1815 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Business Papers: Asylum Company legal disputes, 1809-1822 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Business Papers: John Read, Secretary of the Asylum Company, with the Bank of the United States account book, 1810 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Business Papers: Correspondence, indenture, petition, Samuel Dickinson's will draft, 1810 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Business Papers: Legal papers, correspondence, account information, 1810-1842 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Business Papers: Correspondence, judgment bond, financial information, 1811 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Business Papers: Papers regarding Peter Gaskell and land dispute, 1811 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Business Papers: Legal notes regarding Thomas Meredith, promissory notes, 1811-1834 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Business Papers: Legal documents concerning Union Canal Company, 1811-1830 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Business papers: Legal history notebook, circa 1812 (Volume 80)
  - Business Papers: Correspondence and financial papers, 1812 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Business Papers: Legal notes, 1812-1818 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Business Papers: Correspondence, financial papers, promissory notes, 1813 January-June (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Business Papers: Correspondence, financial papers, warrant of attorney, 1813 July-December (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Business Papers: Bank of Trenton check stubs written by Samuel Meredith, 1813-1834 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Business Papers: Indentures, legal client correspondence, promissory notes, 1813-1830 (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Business Papers: Notes and correspondence relating to Thomas Kennedy, 1813-1821 (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Business Papers: Court notes, correspondence, correspondence with J. Meredith, 1814 January-June (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Business Papers: Court notes, financial papers, Lee's notes of Kennedy's evidence, 1814 May-December (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Business Papers: Correspondence and account information, 1814-1818 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Business Papers: Bonds, letters of administration, mortgages, warrants, circa 1814 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Business Papers: Correspondence, court notes, financial papers, indentures, 1815 January-August (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Business Papers: Correspondence, financial papers, indentures, 1815 September-December (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Business Papers: Ledger, receipts, check stubs, 1815-1826 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Business Papers: Correspondence, receipts, legal notes, and papers about Rebecca Dickinson's death with correspondence with Philip Dickinson, 1815-1832 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Business Papers: John Read's book of notes on estates and businesses, 1816 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Business Papers: Luzerne County, Pennsylvania, land tract information, correspondence, 1816 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Business Papers: Correspondence, indentures, land tract papers, legal notes, 1816-1819 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Business Papers: Correspondence, financial information, indentures, 1817 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Business Papers: Account book for Philadelphia Bank, 1819 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Business Papers: Correspondence, court cases, indentures, loan agreements, 1818 January-June (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Business Papers: Correspondence, Luzerne County, Pennsylvania land tract information, financial information, 1818 July-December (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Business Papers: Indentures and papers regarding Philadelphia Mayor Alderman, 1818-1823 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Business Papers: Correspondence, insurance policies, court summons, 1819 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Business Papers: Thomas Meredith memorandum book, 1819 (Volume 81)
  - Business Papers: Court summons for Philadelphia Bank to Debtors, 1819-1824 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Business Papers: Sherriff's sales, 1819-1824 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Business Papers: Legal notes, receipts, election information, 1819-1832 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Business Papers: Correspondence, court case notes and papers, indentures, 1820 (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Business Papers: Court summons for Philadelphia Bank loans, 1820-1828 (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Business Papers: Legal notes regarding David Ross and M. Cadwalader, 1820-1828 (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Business Papers: Papers regarding Episcopal Fund, 1820-1837 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Business Papers: Correspondence, court case papers, financial information, 1821 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Business Papers: Correspondence, financial papers, indentures, 1822 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Business Papers: Expense book for John Read, Treasurer of the State Convention, 1822 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Business Papers: Account book for Philadelphia Bank (number 2), 1822 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Business Papers: Farmers and Mechanics Bank check stubs and promissory notes written by John Meredith Read, 1822-1827 (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Business Papers: Farmers and Mechanics Bank check stubs and promissory notes written by John Meredith Read, 1822-1827 (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Business Papers: Correspondence, receipts, account information, 1822-1829 (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - Business Papers: Correspondence, legal notes, 1823 (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - Business Papers: Accounts, land tract papers, mortgages, legal notes, correspondence, 1823-1839 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Business Papers: Correspondence, Luzerne County land tract information, 1824 (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Business Papers: Correspondence, legal notes, 1825 (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Business Papers: Correspondence, indentures, legal notes, 1826 (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Business Papers: Correspondence, account information, receipts, 1826-1828 (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Business Papers: Correspondence and notes related to family, legal, academic, and financial matters, circa 1826 (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Business Papers: Correspondence and notes related to family, legal, academic, and financial matters, circa 1826 (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Business Papers: Correspondence, legal notes, court case papers, 1827 (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Business Papers: Correspondence, financial papers, legal notes and papers, mortgages, 1828 (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Business Papers: Correspondence, financial papers, 1829 (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Business Papers: Account book with Philadelphia Bank (number 4), 1829 (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Business Papers: Promissory notes, Luzerne County land tract information, correspondence, 1830 (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Business Papers: Promissory notes, land tract papers, 1831 (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Business Papers: Court summons, promissory notes, legal correspondence, 1832-1833 (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - Business Papers: Legal notes and correspondence relating to clients Samuel Davis and Gilbert Smith Walker, circa 1832 (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - Business Papers: Checks, 1834 (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - Business Papers: Promissory notes and business correspondence, 1834 (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Business Papers: Legal correspondence, court notes, court summons, promissory notes, 1835-1837 (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Business Papers: Legal correspondence, court notes, promissory notes, 1838-1842 (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Business Papers: [John Read?] Account book with Trenton Bank, 1839 (Volume 82)
  - Business Papers: Correspondence, deeds, notes, 1842-1846 (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Business Papers: Account information, legal papers, correspondence, 1843-1850 (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - Business Papers: Legal correspondence, promissory notes, 1846-1849 (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - Business Papers: Account of Family Expenses book, 1848 (Volume 83)